我想其他人都死了
I guess everybody else is dead...
意味着敌人数量远超过我们
Which means we're totally outnumbered.
我们得用强大的火力弥补
We got to make up for that in pure firepower.
你是想袭击补给区  对吧
You want to raid the feeding area, don't you?
那里面有两箱手榴弹
Two boxes of grenades in there.
这是突围的唯一机会
It's our only chance at getting out.
文森  那是个死亡陷阱
Uh, Vince, that place is a death trap.
幸亏  我有大型冲击波枪
Lucky for you, I've got the mega-blaster.
李  你抄右  雷  你从正前方进攻
Lee, you go right. Roy, straight down the middle.
我来掩护你们
I'll cover you both.
一  二  三
1, 2, 3!
掩护到哪去了
Where's that cover fire?
用大型冲击波枪啊  老兄
Mega-blaster, dude. Mega-blaster!
搞什么鬼
Aah! What the hell?
到手了  文森  你哪儿去了
Got it! Vince, where are you?
我甩不掉它们
Ah, I can't get them off of me!
文森你这个窝囊废  跑哪儿了
Vince, you d-bag, where are you?
该死
Damn it. Damn it.
有没搞错  文森
Damn it, Vince.
你觉得这血腥场面好玩吗
That blood look funny to you?
还在改进中  那个编码有点乱
Still working on it. The code's a little janky.
老板  你就忍心这么看着我们
Hey, boss, you just like watching us
被打得屁滚尿流吗
Get our asses shredded?
不是想说你不够积极
Yeah, not that you're not hilarious,
但我们三个月内就要上市啊
But we hit the shelves in three months.
文森
Vince?
文森  你怎么了
Vince, what's wrong?
我的手被火烧一样疼
My hands. They're on fire.
神经传导速度测试正常  排除腕管综合症
Your NCV test was normal. Rules out carpal tunnel.
没有明显外伤  您的血液循环正常
No evidence of trauma. Your blood work looks normal.
-那我得什么病  -我也不知道
- Then what is it? - I don't know.
我会将你转去神经专科
I'll arrange to have you transferred to a neurologist.
神经专科吗
A neurologist?
你们这不是有个名声在外的诊断专家吗
Don't you have some famous diagnostics guy?
他干嘛去了
What's he doing?
我辞职
I quit.
你不能辞职
You can't quit.
我猜你把我和葛伦霍弄混了[断背山男主角]
I think you're confusing me with Jake Gyllenhaal.
-豪斯  你还好吗 -很好  而且我想保持这样
-House, are you okay?-Yeah, and I want to stay that way.
我的心理医生说
Talked it over with my therapist.
我需要改变我的生活环境  习惯
I need to change my environment, my habits.
可他准你把行医执照拿回来了
But he cleared you to get your license back.
所以对我找份新的研究性工作很有帮助
Which will help immensely with my new job in research.
我发出了几份简历
I've sent out some resumes.
做研究就不用看病人  更小的压力
Research means no patients, less pressure.
你才刚出来
Well, you just got out.
你花时间想透彻了吗
Have you had enough time to think this through?
对不起
I'm sorry.
我知道这会影响到你们俩
I know this will affect both of you...
还有十三
And Thirteen...
还有大鼻子情圣
And the one with the nose.
我只是不能冒险回来这里
I just can't risk coming back here.
好吧
Okay.
真是出乎意料
That was surprising.
我想领导这个部门
I want to run the department.
你能在豪斯彻底走人之后
You consider waiting until House clears the lobby
再对他的位置虎视眈眈行吗
Before you start angling for his job?
他不是过世或耍脾气  而且要有人来领导
He's not dead or sentimental and somebody needs to do it.
并非必须的
Not necessarily.
诊断科并不存在
Departments of diagnostic medicine don't exist.
我们设这个部门是因为有豪斯
The only reason we have one is because of House.
你重新给我们分配了职务
You reassigned us,
给了我们三个月工资
Kept us on payroll for three months.
你也同样可以给我一次机会
You might as well give me a chance.
你是个好医生
You're a great doctor.
我希望你留在神经专科
I want you to stay on in neuro.
豪斯是个天才
But House was a genius.
豪斯也是个任性的  官司缠身的瘾君子
House was an egotistical, pill-popping lawsuit magnet...
同时也是个天才
And a genius.
我跟他共事比任何人都久
And I worked with him longer than anybody else.
我能胜任的
I can do this.
你只有一次机会
You get one shot.
豪斯要做什么
What's House gonna do?
不知道  可他走了
No idea, but he's gone.
还是将注意力放在解决医学难题上吧
So how about we focus on the medicine?
-干嘛  -你成我上司了
- What? - You're the boss.
挺性感的
It's kind of sexy.
我以为他只是换了条裤子
Here I thought it was just the pants.
糖尿病性神经病变
Uh, diabetic neuropathy?
糖化血色素正常
Hba1c looks fine.
可能是甲状腺机能减退
Could be hypothyroidism.
没有疲劳或增重的症状
No fatigue or weight gain.
那是复合性局部疼痛综合症吗
What about complex regional pain syndrome?
想法不错
That's a good idea.
做相关测试  瞧瞧我们
Let's run with it. Look at that.
没有豪斯  工作照旧
No House, the job still gets done.
还是少了什么
And yet something's missing.
我矮  他黑
I'm short. He's black.
你断背  有点
You're gay-ish.
-所言极是 -按复合性局部疼痛综合症治疗
-That's it.-Treat for CRPs.
用脊椎刺激疗法
Prep the patient for spinal stimulation.
我不相信
I don't buy it.
复合性局部疼痛综合症不太好理解
CRPs isn't that well understood,
我认为是汞中毒
But I think it's mercury poisoning.
我吃了很多寿司
I eat a ton of sushi.
你这个医学菜鸟是刚刚才从网上学来的吧
And you're currently getting mixed reviews in speed-the-plow on broadway.
搜索一下
Google it.
食用鱼类难以
It's pretty hard to consume enough fish
导致汞中毒
to give yourself mercury poisoning,
而且汞中毒并不会单单表现为疼痛
And it doesn't usually present solely with pain.
是可以的
But it can.
看这大西洋医学杂志
Check out the Atlantic Medical Journal.
这个人因灼烧感疼痛入院
This guy came in with burning pain
病因是由汞中毒导致的
Caused by, uh, "erythromelalgia"
红斑性肌痛症
caused by mercury poisoning.
有网络后谁还会要医生呢
Who needs actual doctors when you got the internet?
恕我冒犯  可是医生也会犯错
No offense, but doctors make mistakes.
医疗失误率今年高达百分之三十
Medical errors are up 30% this year.
你再对比一下病人自己的误诊率
You should check the rate of patient error.
网络信息包罗万象
There's a ton of information out there.
我何不为自己自学一下
Why wouldn't I educate myself, be my own advocate?
我也有查过复合性局部疼痛综合症
CRPs came up in my search too.
可我从没出现肤色异常
But I've never had any skin discoloration,
而且我的疼痛是偶发而不是持续性的
And my pain is sporadic and not constant.
肯定值得做个恶心的血检
It's got to be worth one lousy blood test.
你知道豪斯看人家摸他的球会有什么反应
You know how House feels about people touching his ball.
不知道  奇斯不肯告诉我
No. Chase refuses to tell me.
对  我老公是断背  说不过你
Right. My husband's gay. Witty.
我听说你要接替豪斯
I hear you're taking over for House.
你会大有作为  恭喜你
You're gonna be great. Congratulations.
还未确定永久性
Not permanent.
现在不是而已  陶博和十三同意吗
Yet. Taub and Thirteen cool with it?
陶博比你年长
He's older than you.
十三跟你玉帛相见
She's seen you naked.
说得我们不像是已经两年没有一起工作的样子
Not like we haven't been working together for two years now.
一起工作  与为你工作是不同的
Working with is different than working for.
你见过豪斯了
You saw House.
他怎样
How was he?
他
He was...
挺好
Good.
诚实  有责任感
He was honest, took responsibility.
还有些诡异
It was kind of weird.
十三在这边吗
Uh, is Thirteen around?
急诊室移交文件要她签字
I need her to sign off on her E.R. transfer.
她和陶博在给病人做骨髓刺激
She and Taub are doing a spinal stimulation.
他们没有
No, they're not.
我才刚去过导管室
I just dropped a patient in the cath suite,
你的手下不在那里
And your guys were not in there.
知道吗  骨髓刺激疗法
You know, usually spinal stimulation
跟病人在导管室里做的
Is done with the patient in the room.
他叫我们测试他血液中的汞含量
He asked us to test his blood for mercury.
虽然不太可能  也并非毫无可能
It's unlikely, but not impossible.
-也不是我们的结论  -一个测试并不碍事
- It's also not what we agreed on. - Testing doesn't hurt.
只需要二十分钟  我觉得没关系
It only takes 20 minutes. I figured it didn't matter.
我是觉得
I'm thinking
有没有关系是由我来决定
I should decide when it matters.
在你发完官威之后
When you're done marking your territory...
测试结果
Test results.
惊喜  惊喜啊
Surprise, surprise.
马·韦伯错了[医学喜剧主角]
Marcus Webly was wrong.
我来处理
I'll handle this.
你以为自己不会百感交集吗
You expected not to have mixed feelings?
我知道决定是正确的
I know it's the right call.
只是不知道怎么打发时间
Just don't know what to do with my time.
我的腿痛日益加剧
And my leg
疼痛加剧得很厉害
pain's flared up
从我离开梅菲尔德后
since I left Mayfield.
布洛芬毫无作用
Ibuprofen's barely putting a dent in it.
-你要养成一个爱好  -是的
- You need a hobby. - Right.
全世界的医生都是让病人收集可爱小陶俑 来治疗慢性疼痛\
Doctors the world over treat chronic pain with collections of Hummel figurines.
我并不是说你要建立很烂的爱好
No, I didn't say you need a lame hobby.
你需要能让你集中精力的
You need something to keep you engaged,
能让你与人交往的爱好
Connected to other people.
你已经让我找了个室友
You already made me get a roommate.
威尔森只有一间卧室
Wilson's got one bedroom.
再进一步咱俩就只能脱裤子了
I don't think we can get any more connected without unzipping.
好吧
Okay.
那威尔森有什么爱好呢
So what does Wilson like to do?
文森  我是福曼医生  诊断部门的主管
Vince, I'm Dr. Foreman, head of diagnostics.
你就是代替那个天才的人
So you must be the genius' replacement.
我倾向于觉得自己是天才2.0版
I prefer to think of myself as genius. 2.0.
你的验血结果排除了汞中毒
Your blood tests ruled out mercury poisoning.
-我的汞指数是多少  -2.8
- What was my mercury level? - 2.8.
-就是意味着每1/10公升就 -我知道意味什么
-That means for every deciliter of... -I know what it means.
我也知道高出正常标准
I also know it's above normal.
我想要汞螯合治疗
I want mercury chelation.
你的汞指数还不至于导致你现在的症状
Your level isn't elevated enough to produce your symptoms.
除非我们降低它的水平我会不会改善
You can't know that until we de-elevate it
你才能判断
And see if my pain improves.
这是我的主管判断
It's a judgment call.
根据你10年的医疗培训吗
Based on ten years of medical training?
我认为是复合性局部疼痛综合症
I think you have CRPs.
我想尝试刺激脊髓
I want to try spinal stimulation.
所以简单说来凭你美其名曰的直觉
So, basically, you want to shove a needle in my spine
我坚持做螯合治疗
I'll stick with the chelation.
如果你不想好转那就这样吧
If you don't want to get better, I think we're done.
就这样吧是什么意思
What do you mean "done"?
既然你对我的治疗建议不感兴趣
You're not interested in my medical opinion.
那我要去看下一位病人了
I'll move on to my next patient.
你可以找另外一个医生
You'll move on to a doctor willing to run
给你做那些根本没必要的测试
All the unnecessary tests and procedures you want.
或者就待在这儿治疗
Or you can stick around and be cured.
对我来说没什么不同
Makes no difference to me.
我很高兴你改变主意了
I'm glad you changed your mind.
我怎么不知道
Don't know about that
福曼医生强迫我的
Doctor. Foreman basically strong-armed me,
令我印象深刻
Which is impressive.
100赫兹刺激
Stimulating at 100 Hertz.
我猜你肯定发现
Guess you found him
他比我们两个更善于说服人
A little more persuasive than two of us...
尤其是裤子
Probably the pants.
他让我想起我自己
He reminds me of me.
-会痛吗  -正确操作是不会痛的
- Is it supposed to hurt? - Not if we're in correctly.
手痛还是背痛
Is it your hands? Your back?
不是  是胸口
No, my chest.
喘不过气了
Can't breathe.
心率140  还在上升
Heart rate's 140, climbing.
不要动
You need to hold still.
你们做了什么
What did you do?
深呼吸
Deep breaths.
他肺里开始积水了
His lungs are filling with fluid.
检查过文森肺部的液体
Analysis of the fluid from Vince's lungs
结果显示实际上是心脏的问题
Shows the lung problem is really a heart problem.
他左心室在变厚
He's got a thickened left ventricle.
做脊髓刺激时心脏加速
When his heart sped up during the procedure,
压力就到达肺部
It jacked up the pressure in his lungs,
导致肺水肿
Causing pulmonary edema.
还好我让他做了脊髓刺激
Good thing I talked the patient into spinal stimulation.
让我们发现了新症状
It did lead us to discovering a new symptom
也证明了汞中毒是不成立的
And proved he was wrong about mercury poisoning.
很幸运发现这个
We lucked into that discovery,
同时对复合性局部疼痛综合症的判断错了
And we were wrong about CRPs.
心室增厚外加神经病
Ventricular thickening plus neuropathy
-和莱姆病一样了  -还有关节痛
- Could equal Lyme disease. - Not without joint pain.
他的新游戏是什么时候完成的呢
When is his new game coming out?
几个月了
Couple months.
他肯定不停的工作
He's probably working nonstop.
可能用了比咖啡还有提神的东西
Might be using more than coffee to power through.
可卡因可以解释这个症状
Cocaine use explains the symptoms.
那我们就去他的办公室检查
So we search his office for drugs.
不要
No.
我们去问他
We're gonna ask him.
烹饪在很多方便都和音乐很相似
In a lot of ways, cooking is like music.
不同的音符组成交响乐
Different elements combine to make a symphony.
不同之处是贝多芬第五交响乐
Difference is that Beethoven's 5th
不会在第二天被拉出来
Isn't gonna be poop tomorrow.
我同意让你跟着我的唯一条件
What was my one condition for allowing you
-是什么  -不要像混蛋一样
- To tag along? - Try not to be a jerk.
我在努力  但失败了
I'm trying. I'm just failing.
好好做你的肉丸  保持心态开放
Roll your meatballs and keep an open mind.
要你现在试着不开肉丸的玩笑有多难呢
How hard are you trying not to make a ball joke right now?
冒烟了
You're smoking.
你的肉丸
The balls.
不  不
No, no.
变色太快了
They're browning way too fast.
你要小心的就是蓝色
Blue is the color you got to watch out for.
够了
Enough.
天哪  里面还是生的
My god, they're... They're still raw inside.
等里面煮熟
By the time they're cooked through,
外面就已经焦了
The outside will be burned.
有一种药粉可以防止那样
I think there's a medicated powder for that.
醋也可以
Although vinegar could work.
我化学教授说过  理论上说
My o-chem prof talked about how, theoretically,
一个慢性酸中毒病人的糖化血红蛋白
You shouldn't trust the results of a hemoglobin A1C test
测试结果不是完全准确的
On a chronically acidotic patient.
血液中的酸会减慢
The acid in the blood slows the reaction
血色素蛋白和血糖的反应
Between the hemoglobin protein and blood sugar.
煮肉也是一样的
Browning meat is the same chemical process,
也就是说可以用酸来放慢煮熟速度
Which means, it should also be slowed by acid.
听起来像那么回事
That actually makes sense.
你也许能挽救我的丸子
You might've... saved my balls.
这就对了
That's the spirit.
很明显测试没有像我们预想的
Obviously, the procedure didn't go as planned.
心脏问题是不可预测的
The heart problem was unforeseeable,
但我觉得我还是有责任
But I still feel responsible.
-对不起  -没关系
- I'm sorry. - Okay.
你们做多久了
How long you guys been doing it?
我认为
I think it's best
我们最好专业点
If we kept things professional.
很难
Tough to do
我现在看到你穿着豹纹比基尼
Now that I've seen you rock a leopard-print bikini.
顺便祝贺你们
Congrats, by the way. Up top.
你黑了我的个人主页
You hacked my profile page?
你的治疗差点让我心脏病发作
Your treatment nearly gave me a heart attack.
所以我要查一下你到底有没有资格
Figured I'd check if you had the credentials
给我做一个接一个的检查
One search led to another.
是她吗  我可以做屏保
Is there a shot of just her? I'm thinking screen saver.
我们需要知道你有没有用可卡因
We need to know if you've been using cocaine.
没有  兄弟  你封闭了所有人
Nope. Dude, you just block everybody,
还是你真的有三个朋友吗
Or do you really only have three friends?
你要对我们坦白
We need you to be straight with us.
你必须说实话
We need to be able to trust you.
我12年前戒掉了
I cleaned up my act 12 years ago...
那是在我室友滥用之后
After my college roommate O.D.D.
好吧
Okay.
检查他的办公室
Search his office.
你觉得他没说实话
You think he was lying?
不  但我还不确定
No. But I'm not sure.
刚才应该问他
It was worth asking.
如果他说是  我们就省得跑一趟了
If he'd have said yes, it would've saved us a trip.
但他没有
But he didn't.
你应该忘掉他
You have to forget about him.
-病人吗  -豪斯
- The patient? - House.
一开始你想和他一样  但行不通
First, you try acting like him. That doesn't work.
所以你就走相反路线
So then you try the opposite.
现在你生气是因为不得不用回他的招数
Now you're mad because you have to use his move.
我觉得自己像汤姆·布雷迪的替补
I feel like Tom Brady's backup.
汤姆·布雷迪的替补可以挣1千万吗
Tom Brady's backup now makes $10 million.
别再比较了
Stop comparing.
做你自己就很好
You can do this by being you.
我们还是要检查他的办公室
We should still check out his office,
跟他同事了解一下
Talk to his coworkers.
我和陶一起去
I'll get Taub.
还有
And...
谢谢你
Thanks.
对了  晚上7:00一起吃饭
Oh, and dinner tonight at 7:00.
可以改到8:00吗
Can we make it 8:00?
已经定了7:00的位子了
Already made a reservation for 7:00.
我正在做土豆团子
I'm making gnocchi.
我不想打扰你
Oh, I didn't mean to intrude.
-只是  -塞西尔在上我的烹饪课
- I just... - Cecile's in my cooking class.
她不会说英语
She doesn't speak English.
如果你要烤土豆
If you bake the potatoes
水分就比煮土豆少
Instead of boiling them, it's less moisture,
少点麸粉  团子颜色就浅
Fewer gluten bonds, lighter gnocchi.
-你看起来不错  -感觉好多了
- You seem good. - Feeling better.
豪斯  我想和你谈一下
House, I need to talk to you
关于你离开医院的事情
About your leaving the hospital.
我是喜欢低声下气
I do love a good groveling,
-但这是我最终决定  -好的
- But my decision is final. - That's fine
只要你不是因为我离开
As long as I'm not the reason for it.
我知道听起来很自恋  但是
I know that sounds completely narcissistic, but...
是的
Yeah.
但不是这样的
But it's not.
我们调情接吻
We flirted. We kissed.
我爱抚你
I fondled.
我幻觉  我们共度了一个夜晚
I hallucinated a night with you
还在医院的阳台上喊出来
And yelled it from a hospital balcony.
你不是自恋的人
You're not a narcissist.
那我是什么
So what am I?
不是我离开的原因
Not the reason I'm leaving.
豪斯
House...
我会想你的
I'm gonna miss you.
女士  要么吻她要么离开
Lady, either kiss him or leave.
我们还要工作
We got work to do.
你就不能不说话吗
You just couldn't keep your trap shut.
做你的团子吧
Make the damn gnocchi.
再见
Bye.
我猜你肯定不急着回办公室
I guess you're not in a hurry to get back to the office.
你着急吗
And you are?
我不用避开我男朋友
I'm not trying to avoid my boyfriend.
我是蜥蜴  不是白痴
I'm a lizard, not an idiot.
你从一上了车就心情不好
You've been in a crappy mood since we got in the car.
难道你喜欢被一个24小时前
And you're completely okay with being ordered around
还是和你同级的人随意差遣吗
By someone who 24 hours ago was basically your equal?
我跟你不同  我不想被区别对待
Unlike you, I didn't expect anything different.
在工作上  我会慢慢适应
The work part, I can get used to.
他没邀请我去吃晚餐
He didn't ask me to go to dinner.
他只是通知我
He told me we were going.
他以前从不这样
He's never done that before.
为了打平手
So even the score
晚上回家
Go home tonight,
穿上高跟鞋  把他当小马骑
Put on some heels, and break him like a pony.
你会感觉好些的
You'll feel much better.
怎么了
What?
就是那个
Wow, that's one
巨型鸟
Big-ass bird.
这太逼真了
It's kind of amazing.
这些翅膀的扇动跟真的一样
The way the wings move, it's so real.
滚开啊
Get them off me!
我知道病人怎么了
I know what's wrong with the patient.
我去告诉福曼
I'm going to call Foreman.
救救我
Little help.
你的拍档说是那些该死的鸟提升游戏的真实度
Your partner said you studied birds to improve the game animation.
你碰过他们吗
Did you touch them?
不接触怎么解剖
Can't dissect without touching.
这是了解他们生理结构的最好方法
It's the best way to understand the anatomy.
也是传染鹦鹉病的最好途径
It's also a good way to contract an infection called psittacosis.
我们和福曼医生谈过了
We spoke to Dr. Foreman.
我们想开始使用抗生素
He wants to start you on antibiotics.
是那感染引发的
Does that infection cause problems in the...
勃起问题吗
Joystick area?
我有点走火入魔了
I'm kind of stuck in play mode.
我懂了  她的确美艳动人
Yes, we get it. She's very, very pretty.
不是因为她
It's not her.
是三小时前当她和她男朋友在这的时候
I mean, it was when she was here with her boyfriend three hours ago.
你已经勃起了三个小时了吗
You've had an erection for three hours?
开始  只是有些尴尬
At first, it was just embarrassing,
但是现在开始疼了
But now it's really starting to hurt.
抗生素会缓解症状吗
Will the antibiotics help?
我想不会  这不是鹦鹉热
I'm afraid not. This isn't psittacosis.
即使是在服用药物之后  他仍持续勃起
His erection persisted even with medication.
我们需要植入分流器来疏导血液
We had to put in a surgical shunt just to drain the blood.
你爽约了
You missed dinner.
而且植入分流器不需要动用你们俩
And a shunt doesn't require both of you.
我对工作一腔热诚
I'm dedicated.
心脏  手  还有他的小弟弟
Heart, hands, hose.
可能是格林巴利综合症
Could be guillain-barre.
神经传导正常
Not with normal nerve conduction.
血小板增多症
Thrombocytosis.
血小板数量没那么高
His platelet count isn't that high.
脑瘤更合理些
Brain tumor makes more sense.
不好意思  我只是突然想到
I'm sorry. I just realized...
关节痛和交合之痛
Joint pain and joint pain.
我不是有意想笑你们两个闹别扭的
Honest, I wasn't laughing because of the obvious tension between the two of you.
勃起是循环系统问题造成的
Erection points to a circulatory problem.
我同意福曼
I'm with Foreman.
脑瘤可能会导致
It is possible for a brain tumor to cause
按血小板增多症治疗
We're going with thrombocytosis.
好吧
Okay.
你就因为我没邀你去吃晚餐生气
You're mad I didn't ask you to dinner?
我们已经在一起多久啦
How long have we been dating?
就像是你在命令我
It felt like an order.
-你说话的调调  -我的调调
- Your tone of voice was - My tone?
我现在压力很大
I'm under a little pressure right now.
让我喘口气好吗
How about giving me a break?
听着  这对你我都很难
Look, this is tough for both of us,
只是我不像你  能当上部门头头
Except I haven't just gotten a promotion.
这么说  你嫉妒了
So now you're jealous.
不是  我只是让你别冲着手下发牢骚
No. I'm just saying don't complain the burden of command to your employee
我是跟我女朋友发牢骚而已
I was complaining to my girlfriend.
他们是谁
Who are those guys?
不知道
I have no idea.
要一较高下了
Meet the competition.
斯蒂芬·鲍尔森  圣马克医院的神经科医生
Steve Paulson. Neurology, St. Mark's.
幸会
Nice to meet you.
-你请了别的医生  -还有很多别的医生
- You called another doctor? - Lots of other doctors.
我把我的症状发在了网上
Posted my symptoms on the internet.
你们连败两局
You guys are 0 for 2.
我得找些外援
I thought I'd look for some backup.
用木瓜毒素清洁可以消除你的所有症状
I can cure all your symptoms with my papaya toxin cleanse.
每个月395美元
Month's supply, $395.
虽然这家伙没脑  但那不意味全都是
Okay, that guy's an idiot. That doesn't mean they all are.
你们在这所医院没有行医特权
Neither one of you have privileges at this hospital.
请离开
Please leave...
现在就走
Now.
福曼医生  我想请问一下
Uh, DR. Foreman, sorry for the intrusion,
你还没给他做过头部核磁共振扫描
But, um, I noticed you haven't done a head MRI yet.
因为他不需要
Cause he doesn't need one.
我认为他有脑瘤
I'm pretty sure he's got a brain tumor.
我们考虑过这一可能性
We considered that
并认为血小板增多症是最可能的
And concluded thrombocytosis is more likely.
我准备给他服用羟基脲
I'm starting him on hydroxyurea.
他的血小板数量根本就没超标
His platelets don't seem anywhere near high enough.
如果你拍个片子  我肯定你会
If you took an image, I'm sure you'll
没有颅内压上升的迹象
There are no signs of increased ICP.
我不是在延缓治疗
I'm not delaying treatment.
看来要打破僵局了
Looks like we need a tiebreaker.
哈德利医生  你怎么想呢
Dr. Hadley, what do you think?
我认为两个理论都有可取之处
I think both theories have merit.
所以要么是脑瘤
So brain tumor,
要么就是为了支持你那男友上司
Otherwise you'd back your boss/boyfriend.
我要做核磁共振扫描
I want an MRI.
好  我来安排
Fine. I'll set it up.
太好了  你起来了  正要一个人来试味
Great. You're up. I need a taster.
法式蔬菜炖猪肉香肠
Ragout with pork sausage,
牛腿肉  不加奶酪
Beef thigh, no cream.
还很早啊
It's a little early.
你一夜没睡吗
Did you even go to bed last night?
床是给女孩用的
Bed is for sissies,
除非你在做爱
Unless you're having sex, in which case...
也不对  床始终都是给女孩用的
No, bed is still for sissies.
这是不是有点走火入魔啊
Doesn't this seem a little bit obsessive?
我在宰牛的时候你不该来
Should've been here when I was butchering the ox.
你还想怎样  我是个瘾君子
What do you expect? I'm an addict.
十一点我就会把所有东西都打开
I turn everything up to eleven.
那是  我以为你要保持冷静
Yeah. I thought you were trying to tone that down.
在半夜十一点除了玩点
No. I was trying to find something
震耳欲聋的东西还能能干嘛
I could set at eleven without blowing out my eardrums.
焦糖圆葱片配八角
Star anise with caramelized onions.
硫化物幻化出肉的香味
The sulfur compounds bring out the meat flavor.
我腿疼难眠
I couldn't sleep because of my leg.
要么来做炖菜
It was either make ragout
要么去街上招妓
Or go out on the street looking to score.
真是天作之合
Good choice.
好好吃
So, so good.
他问我  我如实回答
He asked me a question. I answered.
你要我自己做决定
You told me to make my own decisions.
我照做  你却在背后放冷箭
I do, and you stab me in the back.
我已经把我隐瞒了自己的真实想法
I didn't even say what I really thought.
我被置身事外  我不喜欢这样
I hedged, and I don't like that I hedged.
-如果我有合理的想法  -私下讨论
- If I have a legitimate opinion - You express it in private.
在公众场合  团队的意见就是你的意见
In public, the team opinion is your opinion.
可现在团队的意见  变成是你的个人意见
Except the team opinion is your opinion.
那是就我的职责
That's my job.
那我的呢
And what's mine,
就是要我被质问的时候撒谎吗
To lie when I'm asked a direct question?
你会为了豪斯这么做
You would've done it for House.
也许你只是不想让我成功
Maybe you just don't want me to succeed.
也许你只是为了晚餐的事再教训我一次
Maybe you just want to kick me again for not asking you to dinner.
至少当豪斯变成不可理喻的混蛋时
At least when House was being an unbelievable jerk,
我可以跟我的男友抱怨
I could talk to my boyfriend about it.
也许我就是个混蛋
I may be a jerk,
但是你错了
But you're wrong.
核磁共振检查正常
MRI is clean.
治疗他的血小板增多症
Treat him for thrombocytosis
你来早了
You're early
你在等什么
For what?
我知道你会来这向我抱怨福曼
I knew you'd show up here complaining about Foreman.
原以为你能多撑一个星期
Thought you'd hold out for another week at least.
我只是想问你是否遇过
I showed up to ask if you've seen
低血小板数的血小板增多症
Thrombocytosis with a platelet count under
我是疯了  可我不傻
I went crazy, not stupid.
我离开
I leave,
福曼终于如愿以偿
Foreman embraces his inner mugabe.
那是什么
What's that?
毛鸡蛋  未孵化的鸡蛋
Embryonali, unhatched chicken egg.
我准备吸出一些蛋黄
I'm gonna suck out some of the yolk
把它换成炖菜料
And replace it with ragout.
你顺便告诉其他的麻风病人
By the way, you can tell the other lepers
我知道他们不来了
That their absence has been noted.
卡梅隆没来过吗
Cameron didn't come by?
爸爸的红颜知都已经发育完全了
Daddy's little co-dependent is all grown up.
给跟男友闹别扭的辣妹有机可乘
Making room for daddy's hot bisexual with boyfriend problems.
我们之间没有问题
It's not a problem. It's, um...
好吧  我们是有问题
Okay. It's a problem.
我知道
I mean, I get it.
这个病人像个噩梦
The patient's a nightmare.
他将他的病例发到网上了  你了解福曼
He posted his case online. You know Foreman.
你了解整个状况
You know the situation.
我怎么叫他保持冷静
How can I get him to tone it down?
首先  别再唯唯是诺
Stop being a coward for one thing.
他是个很害怕失败的人
He's the one who's afraid of failure.
要做我没做过的工作
At a job that no one before me has ever done.
他的恐惧是正常
His fears are justified.
可你却一心只怕他会完全控制你
You're just afraid of giving him control over you,
虽然在家里这样没什么不好
Which might work at home.
你的抗拒阻碍了他的工作
It makes it almost impossible for him to do his job.
把饼干递给我
Pass me those crackers.
你的意思是这都怪我吗
You're saying this is all my fault?
我的意思是
I'm saying
懂得适时让步  自己会快乐些
That you would be happier if you learned when it's okay to give in.
你是什么
What?
你说我只有作出让步
You just suggested that I give in
才能变得快乐
So that I can be happy.
他们在那里对你施了什么法
What did they do to you in there?
尝尝这个
Taste this.
很好吃
Mmm. Good.
是我吃过的最美味的东西
This might be the best thing I've ever eaten.
比你现在能想到的还要好
And, yes, I'm including what you're thinking of now.
你厨艺太棒了
You are an amazing cook!
我知道
I know.
可惜我的腿还是痛
And yet, my leg hurts.
炒了她
Fire her.
我没想炒她
I'm not gonna fire her.
那就别那么多心
Then stop being such a wuss.
我哪里多心了
I'm not being a wuss.
质疑你的工作也是她的职责
Challenging you is part of her job.
只不过质疑的人是她  你就感情用事
But when she does it, you take it personally.
你是说我错了吗
So you're saying this is my fault?
我只是想大事化小
I was trying to bury it a little, but, yeah.
你要么就除掉质疑你的人 要么别再小题大作
You got to eliminate either the challenge or the reaction.
我倒是觉得该按原计划进行
Or we could stick with my original plan.
我们喝个烂醉  然后聊起女人的是非
We get drunk and talk about how girls are lame.
好啊
Yeah.
问题自己就会迎刃而解
This problem will go away on its own.
早上八点了
It's 8:00 in the morning.
咖啡味冰激凌
Coffee ice cream.
不做煎蛋饼  也不做栗子泥馅吗
No frittata? No bombolini?
仔细思考过你说我走火入魔话
Started thinking about what you said, about me obsessing.
现在走火入魔般关注走火入魔
Started obsessing about obsessing.
所以决定要休假一天
Decided to take a day off.
你不是很喜欢烹饪吗
You were enjoying cooking.
有哪个正常男人
How like a man
会喜欢整天舞锅弄盆
To think that I enjoy slaving over a hot stove all day
而看着你成天跟漂亮小秘鬼混
While you're off banging secretaries.
是你说它能让你忘记疼痛的
You said it was keeping your mind off the pain.
我发现电视上的减肥胖子更好玩
That was before I discovered the biggest loser marathon on cable.
我假装他们能看见我吃得津津有味
I like to pretend they can see me eating.
你的腿怎么样了
And your leg?
没什么大碍
It's fine.
我腿疼难耐
My leg's killing me.
烹饪刚开始还管用
Cooking helped for a while.
但我很快就厌倦了
I guess I got bored.
我的腿又开始疼痛难忍
My leg started hurting again.
我开始担心  更加重了病情
Then I got worried, and that made the pain worse.
你在担心什么
What are you worried about?
我担心终究无计可施
That nothing's gonna help.
我要在灰暗世界里了解此生
That I end up in the very dark place.
我没事
I'm fine.
只是不开心
Just not happy.
我不是因为你快乐才让你出院
I didn't let you out because you were happy.
我让你出院  是因为我相信
I let you out, because I believe
你有处理事情的能力
You had the skills to cope with that.
你尝试过一次  既然没起作用
You tried one thing. It didn't work.
试点别的
So move on.
写作或是下棋
Write. Play chess.
如果都没用怎么办
What if nothing works?
如果任何事情
What if nothing gives me more
我都坚持不了几天就开始另找新欢
Than a few days before my brain starts looking for the next fix,
而且腿又会像是被人在用钉子猛戳
Before my leg feels like someone's shoving nails into it?
那我该怎么办
What do I do then?
如果真的找不到能抓住你的事物
If nothing in the world can hold your interest,
我们再来解决也为时不晚
Uh, we'll deal with that when we get to it.
但你要信任我  要有耐心
But you have to trust me, and you have to be patient.
我给你买了甜甜圈
I brought you a doughnut.
花店关门了
The florist was closed.
我去拿个花瓶把它养起来
I'll get a vase and put it in water.
我很抱歉
You know I'm sorry, right?
我也有错
I'm sorry too.
你觉得
Do you think, um,
我们能重新来过么
We could start over?
这是个好主意
That's a fantastic idea.
我们会迟到的
We're gonna be late.
你老板不会介意的
Your boss won't mind.
没搞错吧
No way.
他的淋巴结突然涨大
His lymph nodes blew up.
已经按血小板增多症来治疗
He's been treated for thrombocytosis,
但是没什么起色
But there's been no change.
-我诊断有误  -你真是个天才
- I was wrong. - God, you are a genius.
我要把这个加进我的症状表里
I'm adding this to my list of symptoms.
上次也不管用
That didn't work last time.
因为我给的钱不够
Because I didn't think big enough.
这次我要悬赏两万五千元奖金
Now I am offering 25000 dollars reward.
类固醇已经缓解了面部肿大问题
Steroids reduced his facial swelling.
淋巴结肿大排除了血小板增多的可能性
Swollen lymph nodes rule out thrombocytosis.
怎么大家都知道我的邮箱地址
How did so many people get my personal email?
网络是个神奇的领域
The internet is a magical place.
淋巴肿大表明可能是多动脉炎
Lymph enlargement makes me think polyarteritis
你刚刚说什么
You were saying?
没必要揪着着症状不放  而忽视了病根
No point in treating the symptom and not the disease.
你那吸引人的广告有不少答复嘛
Your stunt generated quite a few responses.
来看看吧
Let's take a look.
我早就看过了
I'm way ahead of you.
可能是脊椎肿瘤引起的副肿瘤综合症
Paraneoplastic syndrome secondary to spinal tumor.
不是  没有出现血钙过多
No. No hypercalcemia.
也没有肌肉痉挛以及大小便失禁的症状
No muscle spasms or incontinence.
你被圣经里的"邪恶军团"附身
You are possessed by the biblical demon "Legion."
也不是  没有从悬崖跳到猪圈里
No, no jumping off a cliff in a herd of pigs.
要不然就真的命中
Otherwise it did fit.
甲状腺机能亢进
Graves' disease.
不是  他的甲状腺水平正常
No. Thyroid levels are normal.
你想让我们一直花时间排除所有可能选项
You want us to spend the next few days shooting down every theory in the world,
还是让我们好好工作
Or can we do our jobs
想出一个解决方案呢
And come up with one that works?
我要你们给我做淀粉样变性病测试
I want you to test me for amyloidosis.
这就是你的专业意见吗
That's your professional opinion?
这是头脑风暴的结果
It's the wisdom of crowds.
研究表明集体判断
Studies show the collective decision of a group
会比任何个人的判断更加精确
Can be more accurate than any individual's decision.
我已经查阅过所有邮件  淀粉样变性病得票率最高
I went through my emails. Amyloidosis got the most votes.
如果你得了淀粉样变性病
If you had amyloidosis,
你的心脏超声检查会有斑点出现
There'd be speckling on your cardiac ultrasound.
百分之百肯定么
In 100% of cases?
那好
Fine.
我们来做笔交易
I'll make you a deal.
我们会给你做肾脏活体检查测试淀粉样变性
We'll do a kidney biopsy to test for amyloidosis.
如果答案是否定的
When it comes back negative,
你就把自己的病例从网上撤下来
You pull your case off of the internet
并取消悬赏
And retract the reward.
任选其一  否则你连测试都别想做
It's either that, or I don't test you at all.
成交
Deal.
如果你想小干一场的话  就该先给我打个电话
If you wanted a quickie, you should've called ahead.
我现在蓬头垢面的
I'm a mess.
我回来吃中饭而已
Came home for lunch.
你星期二不是要跟卡迪吃饭吗
You have lunch with Cuddy on Tuesdays.
她抽不开身
She was busy.
你只是想打探军情吧
And you are checking up on me.
你什么都可以跟我讲
You know, you can talk to me.
那是我洗好的衣服吗
Is that my laundry?
你已经没袜子借我穿了
You were running out of socks for me to borrow.
不过你的内裤倒是剩了不少
You got plenty of underwear, though.
我很好
I'm fine.
你早上已经说过了
You said that this morning.
持续性证明了什么呢
And consistency proves what?
真的  我很好  我放去你的房间咯
Really. I'm good. I'll put these in your room.
你总是伤害
You always hurt
你爱的人
The one you love
活体检查显示肾脏内皮有沉淀物
Biopsy showed deposits in the renal endothelium
与淀粉样变性症一致
Consistent with amyloidosis.
网上说的是对的
The internet was right.
给他用氟美松[抗炎药]
Start him on dexamethasone.
已经用过了
Already done.
现在说这个可能不太合适
This may not be the best time for this.
我要辞职
But I quit.
一个朋友邀请我加入他的外科诊所
I got an offer to join a friend's surgical practice.
一般来说你不会受聘
Um, you don't generally get an offer
除非你特意去应征
Unless you're looking for one.
当我发现豪斯一去不复返的时候  我就到处求职了
I put out some feelers when I found out House wasn't coming back.
我努力游说上头保留这个部门
I lobbied to keep the department open
才能保住你的工作
So you could keep your job.
是吧  你真是太无私了
Yes. That was incredibly altruistic of you.
不是针对你
It's nothing personal.
你干得很出色
Actually, I think you're doing pretty well.
可是我是为与豪斯共事而来
But I came here to work with House.
他是个混蛋
He's a jerk.
我们没他也能行
We'll be fine without him.
你知道我们每天都能收到多少份简历吗
Do you know how many resumes we get every day without even asking?
卡迪让我们关门大吉之后人会少点
Might be a few less after Cuddy shuts us down.
这个病例是在你的掌管下顺利解决的
The case got solved under your watch.
至于如何解决的有那么重要吗
Does it really matter how it happened?
很重要
It matters.
如果我没准备好坐这个位置怎么办
What if I'm just not ready for this job?
你很沮丧
Okay, you're sad.
我可以给你讲我和室友在劳伦斯学院的事
I could tell you the story about me and my roommate at Sarah Lawrence.
好的
Okay.
她叫琳熙
Her name was Lindsey,
她是来自爱荷华州的拉拉队长
And she was a cheerleader from Iowa.
我今早敲碎了我的厕所
I broke my toilet this morning.
我去抄家伙
I'll get my tools.
我堵住了入水阀
I blocked the intake valve
收集到豪斯的尿液
So I could collect some of house's urine.
卡迪  他几乎不瘸了
Cuddy, he was barely limping.
检测结果是什么
What did the lab say?
尿液里不含维柯丁
The urine was clean for vicodin.
即便如此
It did, however,
却含有一些奇怪的上皮细胞
Contain strange epithelial cells.
进一步的分析显示
Further analysis showed
这些细胞来自于拉布拉多寻物犬
They were from a labrador retriever.
该死
Damn.
他还在服药
He's using.
不  不要
No. No.
文森  文森
Vince. vince.
文森  放松
Vince, relax.
我是福曼医生
It's Dr. Foreman.
杀死它
Kill it!
杀死它  不  不
Kill it! No! No!
我没有冲击枪
I don't have my blaster!
幻觉导致体温上升
He's hallucinating 'cause he's burning up.
淀粉样变性不会这样
Amyloidosis wouldn't do this
退烧药没用
The antipyretics didn't work.
希望冷水浴能帮他降下体温
Hopefully the cold tub will get his temp down.
也许我们应该听听其他人的意见
Maybe we should see if anyone's sent in other ideas.
也许奖金吸引到...
Maybe the reward money attract...
我不会再让任何人将我们耍的团团转
No. I'm not letting anyone else jerk us around.
网络的淀粉样变性诊断是错误的
The masses were wrong about amyloidosis.
他们不知道发烧这一症状
They don't know about the fever.
我认为是轻链沉淀病
I'm going with light-chain deposition disorder.
你觉得呢
You okay with that?
是的
Yes.
我们认为你得是轻链沉淀病
We think you have a disease called lcdd.
这种病导致你的器官里积累了大量蛋白质
It causes protein to build up in your organs.
你认为
You think?
我们还不能绝对的确诊
We can't definitely confirm the diagnosis.
而你唯一痊愈的机会
And our only chance of beating this
就是开始进行高剂量化疗
Would be to start you on high-dose chemotherapy.
但是我必须提醒你
But I do have to warn you
以你的身体状况可能会致命
That in your condition, It might kill you.
你还需要更多信息吗
Do you want me to get you some more information?
你是我的医生
You're my doctor.
我相信你
I trust you.
你并不是相信我
No, you don't.
你只是害怕
You're scared,
害怕自己做决定
And you don't want to make this decision.
我的职业生涯都押在这桩病例上
My career is riding on this case...
但也远不及你的性命重要
Nowhere near as important as your life.
现在最好就是当做轻链沉积治疗
But I think the best shot for both of us is to treat for lcdd.
好的
Okay.
那好  先把你从这个盆里弄出来
All right, let's get you out of this tub
再开始化疗
And into chemo.
我们知道你又服维柯丁
We know you're back on vicodin.
错  你们唯一知道的是我是天才
No. The only thing you know is that I'm a genius
能让一只狗在你的厕所撒尿
Who got a dog to pee in your toilet.
你们不知道我是如何做到的 更有趣的是
You don't know how I did it or, More interestingly,
我是在哪撒的尿
Where I peed.
豪斯  你花了三个月的时间
House, you've spent the last three months
您呢  布鲁图[罗马政治家 意大利语]
Et tu, Butte?
你来这干嘛
You got no reason to be here.
我要整的是他
He's the one I was jerking around.
你的腿为什么不疼了
Why is your leg better?
哎哟  好痛啊
Ow. It hurts.
你们可以走了
Please go away now.
如果你们真的以为我还在用的话
If you really think I'm using,
为什么不在敲破你家水管前先问问我
How about asking me before taking a wrench to your plumbing?
豪斯  你是个瘾君子
House, you're an addict.
你的话很难让人信服
You can't be surprised if we can't take you at your word.
那好  我给你些证据
Fine. Let's get you some proof.
女士们  闭上眼睛
Hide your eyes, ladies.
豪斯
House.
你也一样
You too.
那个杯子是我的教子亲手给我做的
My godson made me that mug.
如果测试结果仍是寻猎犬的话
If the lab says that this is retriever too,
尽快通知我
Please let me know right away.
这能解释我为何总想用你家地毯蹭屁屁
It'd explain my overwhelming desire to wipe my butt on your carpet.
谢谢你把我拽进这趟混水
Thank you for dragging me into this.
停下化疗  他得的是法布雷病
Stop the chemo. He's got fabry's disease.
他在冷水槽里呆了一小时
He was in the tub for an hour.
他的手指应该被冻僵  但是没有
His fingers should have pruned, but they didn't.
已经停止化疗  证实是法布雷病
Already stopped chemo and confirmed fabry's.
很高心你们俩意见一致了
I'm glad you both agree,
但是能否给我解释一下
But could somebody loop me in here?
我们原以为你肾脏的沉积物是蛋白质
We assumed the deposits in your kidneys were proteins,
但实际上时脂肪
But they were fats.
法布雷病会造成脂肪沉积在器官内部  扰乱神经
Fabry's makes them build up in your organs, choke your nerves,
防止你的手指在冰水中冻僵
Keep your fingers from pruning in water.
这是一种慢性病但是可以治愈
It's chronic but manageable.
你怎么想到的
How'd you figure it out?
碘腮腺炎
Iodine mumps.
做了头部扫描后  他的淋巴结肿胀
His lymph nodes swelled up after the head C.T.
我们以为这是一种新的症状 其实不是
We thought it was a new symptom, But it wasn't.
是相对的应激反应
It was a reaction to the contrast.
碘腮腺炎造成了淋巴结肿胀
Iodine mumps takes lymph nodes off the table.
倘若除去这一症状
Remove that symptom...
你就突然灵光闪现吗
And that just came to you?
我看过在线回复
I looked through the online responses again.
今早有个人贴出了这个理论
Someone posted it this morning.
听说卡迪正式任命了
Heard cuddy made it official.
终于当上部门主管了  恭喜
Department's yours. Congrats.
对不起
I'm sorry.
我背着你下结论
I went behind your back.
从一分到十分  你有多生气
On a scale of 1 to 10,how mad are you?
七分
Seven
而且我太蠢了
And that's stupid.
你是对的
You did the right thing.
是我的错逼得你不得不背着我
It's my fault you thought you had to go behind my back.
我应该站出来面对你
I should've stood up to you.
但是你没有  因为你不想和我争吵
But you didn't 'cause you didn't want to fight again.
这是我们的第一个病例 我们慢慢就会适应的
It's our first case. It'll take time to adjust.
如果等到我们都适应了
What if by the time we get adjusted,
我们却已经不爱彼此了呢
We don't like each other anymore?
那不可能
That's not gonna happen.
你确定吗
You sure?
自从我登上这一职位
Cause ever since I took this job,
我们就让彼此苦不堪言
We've been making each other miserable.
我想这样行不通
I really don't think this is gonna work.
你要和我分手吗
You're breaking up with me?
不
No.
那个晚上 我以为我完蛋了  只有你在我身边
The other night. When I thought I was done, you were there.
我需要你
I need you.
我不想失去你
I don't want to lose you.
那你为什么
Why are you...?
你要解雇我
You're firing me.
很抱歉
I'm sorry.
我逃了
I slipped.
你服用了维柯丁吗
You took vicodin?
两万五千元
$25,000.
我解决了我老队员们的病例
I solved my old team's case.
我正准备吃维可丁
I was about to take the pills.
我上网
I went online.
发现有人贴出了医术问题
I found people posting medical problems,
那时
And...
我的腿不痛了
My leg stopped hurting.
我理应改变我的生活
I'm supposed to be changing my life.
这不是改变
This is not a change.
也许我错了
Well, maybe I was wrong.
这是那在我脑里盖沙子城堡的人所说的话吗
Says the guy making sand castles in my brain.
我们要你远离维柯丁
We need to keep you from using.
远离旧工作  远离医疗谜题
Taking your job away, the medical puzzles,
却几乎反而把你推向了旧生活
Nearly drove you back to it.
也许这些诊断药物 是保持你清醒的关键
Maybe diagnostic medicine is the key to keeping you clean.
那你是说让我继续上网解决病例
So you're okay with me going online, solving cases?
你不能成天关在家中
No. You can't sit all day in a room by yourself.
孤独会造成压抑
Isolation fosters depression.
那家医院是我旧生活的一部分
The hospital is part of my old life.
如果我回去的话  我可能变回
If I go back, I might become...
过去的我  一个瘾君子
Who I was before, pills and all.
有这种可能
That's a possibility.
但是也许
But could be...
相对于重新开始吃药更糟的事却是
The only thing worse for you than going back to diagnostic medicine
不让你回去
Is not going back.
答案自有分晓
Guess we're gonna find out.